isi.edu 2011-04-26

# 

University Community (faculty, staff and students)
Privacy of Personal Information
The University of Southern California is committed to the
responsible use of personal information collected from and
about students, faculty, staff, business partners and others
who provide such information to us and to compliance with
both state and federal regulations concerning the use of
personal information. Such personal information includes
any number that may be used, alone or in conjunction with
any other information, to identify a specific individual; or
other personal information that could be used to cause
financial or reputational harm to an individual. This policy
applies to information that is collected by any means
whether electronically, by telephone, or on paper.
Limits on Use and Access
The responsible use of personal information requires that the
university respect individual privacy, protect against identity
theft and other unauthorized uses, and comply fully with all
laws and government regulations i n the collection, use,
storage, display, distribution and disposal of such
information. Authorized uses of personal information within
the university are limited to those which a) are necessary to
meet legal and regulatory requirements; b) facilitate access
to services, transactions, facilities and information; or c)
support efficient academic and administrative processes.
Access to personal information is limited to
    § the individual whose information is produced or
        displayed,
    § a University official or agent of the university with
        authorized access based upon a legitimate academic
        or business interest and a need to know,
Issued by:       Dennis F. Dougherty
                 Senior Vice President,
                 Administration
                 Lloyd Armstrong, Jr.
                 Provost and Senior Vice President,
                 Academic Affairs
Date issued:     December 1, 2004
                 University of Southern California
                 Page 1 of 4

     §   an organization or person authorized by the individual
         to receive the information,
     §   a legally authorized government entity or
         representative, or other circumstances in which the
         University is legally compelled to provide access to
         personal information, or
     §   other individuals or entities, as allowed by law, for
         purposes judged to be appropriate or necessary for
         the reasonable conduct of University business.
Social Security Numbers
State law protects the use of Social Security numbers. The
University will continue to collect and maintain Social
Security numbers in all instances in which that number is
required by law for reporting or other uses. This includes,
but is not limited to, all enrolled students who are U.S.
citizens or permanent residents, and all individuals receiving
payment from the University. In addition, the University will
continue to use Social Security numbers, as allowed b y law,
for operational purposes for which there is no reasonable
substitute. Social Security numbers are always considered
confidential, and therefore subject to the access restrictions
described above.
It is against both state law and university policy to
• Publicly post or display the Social Security number in any
     manner;
• Print the Social Security number on any card required to
     access service;
• Require an individual to transmit his or her Social
     Security number over the Internet unless the connection
     is secure or the number is encrypted;
• Require an individual to use his or her Social Security
     number to access an Internet site unless a unique
     password or PIN is also required; or
• Print a Social Security number on any materials that are
     mailed unless required by a state or federal agency,
     unless state or federal law requires the Social Security
Issued by:         Dennis F. Dougherty
                   Senior Vice President,
                   Administration
                   Lloyd Armstrong, Jr.
                   Provost and Senior Vice President,
                   Academic Affairs
Date issued:       December 1, 2004
                   University of Southern California
                   Page 2 of 4

    number to be on the document to be mailed. Also, Social
    Security numbers may be included in applications and
    forms sent by mail, including documents sent as part of
    an application or enrollment process, or to establish,
    amend or terminate an account, contract or policy, or to
    confirm the accuracy of the Social Security number.
Department and Personal Responsibility
Each university department is responsible for reviewing and
monitoring internal procedures, reports and other documents
to assure compliance with this policy. This responsibility
includes providing training and control systems for the
responsible use of personal information that is accessible to
employees for doing the work of the department. The
University expects that all members of the community also
will exercise caution in making available their own personal
information to others. In particular, individuals should not
give others access to their USC identification cards,
passwords or personal identification number (PIN).
Online Collection of Personal Information
University departments that collect personal information on
their Web pages must post a link to this privacy policy and
inform consumers about a ny persons or entities outside the
university with whom they may share personal information
collected online. If the department has a process for the
consumer to change such information, that process must be
described and available to the consumer on the department
Web pages. Any changes to this privacy policy will be posted
on the USC Web site.
Personal Biomedical Information
Medical records, records pertaining to personal health
information and records pertaining to human subjects in
research projects are governed by more extensive
restrictions. For more information concerning human
subjects research, refer to
http://www.usc.edu/admin/provost/irb.
Issued by:       Dennis F. Dougherty
                 Senior Vice President,
                 Administration
                 Lloyd Armstrong, Jr.
                 Provost and Senior Vice President,
                 Academic Affairs
Date issued:     December 1, 2004
                 University of Southern California
                 Page 3 of 4

Information Requiring Enhanced Protection
In addition to this privacy policy, please refer to the
university’s Information Security Policy for additional security
requirements for personal information and other types of
information that require enhanced privacy protection.
Resources
The following offices have responsibility for providing
interpretation and implementation guidance on this policy.
Questions about the policy should be directed as follows:
Complaints about online collection of personal information or
compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act
Office of Information Security (213) 743-4900
For issues or complaints regarding use or misuse of your
own personal identification information
Students – Dean of Academic Records and Registrar (213)
740-4623
Faculty – Vice Provost for Faculty Affairs (213) 740-6715
Staff – Director, Personnel Services (213) 740-7953
System Access, Security and Access Termination
Administrative Information Services (AIS) (213) 821-2000
Information Services Division (ISD) (213) 740-5555
Vendor/Contractor Access to Information and Confidentiality
Agreements
Disbursement Control (213) 740-2720
Purchasing Department (213) 740-2281
E-Mail and Internet, Intranet, Extranet Uses of Personal
Information and Disposal of Electronic Records and
Computers
Office of Information Security (213) 743-4900
Issued by:        Dennis F. Dougherty
                  Senior Vice President,
                  Administration
                  Lloyd Armstrong, Jr.
                  Provost and Senior Vice President,
                  Academic Affairs
Date issued:      December 1, 2004
                  University of Southern California
                  Page 4 of 4
